EMERGENCY MEDICAL SYSTEM
LAYANAN MEDIS DARURAT
-Are you all right? -Yes.
- Kau baik-baik saja? - Ya.
-Is this where you're staying?
Ini tempat tinggalmu?
Why are you alone?
Kenapa kau sendiri?
Namsuri?
Namsuri?
-I lost him. -How?
- Aku kehilangan dia. - Kok bisa?
It's none of your business.
Bukan urusanmu.
You can't keep living here.
Kau tak bisa terus tinggal di sini.
Have you made up your mind to give me your house and yourself?
Apa kau mau memberikan rumah dan dirimu sendiri?
No, that's not what I meant.
Bukan itu maksudku.
No?
Bukan?
Then what did you mean?
Lalu apa?
I think you should seek help from the welfare system.
Kurasa kau harus mencari bantuan dari sistem kesejahteraan.
I don't understand what that means.
Entah apa maksudmu.
If you haven't decided to dedicate your house and yourself to me,
Jika kau belum mau berikan rumah dan dirimu kepadaku, pergilah.
Did I thank you?
Apa aku sudah berterima kasih?
Yes, you did.
Ya, benar.
Then goodbye.
Kalau begitu, selamat tinggal.
All right.
Baiklah.
I didn't really save your life or anything like that,
Aku tak benar-benar menyelamatkanmu atau semacamnya,
-right? -Sorry?
- benar? - Apa?
Get going.
Pergilah.
You ungrateful wench.
Wanita tak tahu berterima kasih.
You're such an ingrate.
Kau tak tahu terima kasih.
Have a conscience, will you?
Kapan kau sadar?
That's when it started.
Itu permulaannya.
That's when she started
Saat itulah dia mulai...
hearing weird sounds ringing in her ears.
mendengar suara aneh di telinganya.
Well, what I mean is,
Maksudku adalah sesuatu
something keeps talking to her.
- yang terus berbicara dengannya. - Apa?
Flowers and water.
Bunga dan air.
Things like trees, rocks, and ants.
Benda seperti pohon, batu, dan semut.
-And oranges too. -Oranges?
- Juga jeruk. - Jeruk?
At first, it wasn't a big deal at all.
Awalnya, itu bukan masalah besar.
Gosh!
Astaga!
It wouldn't have been strange even if she had thought she misheard it.
Itu tak akan aneh jika dia mengira dia salah dengar.
-I try not to say things like this. -But you're too much.
- Aku berusaha tak katakan ini. - Tapi kau berlebihan.
I'm a plant too.
Aku juga tanaman.
You heartless woman, you killed a cactus!
Wanita jahat, kau bunuh kaktus!
The second time she heard it,
Kali kedua dia mendengarnya,
she just thought it was happening because she was tired.
dia pikir itu terjadi karena dia lelah.
There's nothing to eat in this house.
Tidak ada makanan di rumah ini.
I'll go visit the next-door neighbor.
Aku akan mengunjungi tetanggaku.
The third time she heard it,
Ketiga kalinya dia mendengarnya,
she thought she must be exhausted and just needed some rest.
dia pikir dia pasti kelelahan dan hanya butuh istirahat.
Why do you Korean folks keep pronouncing my name wrong?
Kenapa kalian orang Korea
Repeat after me. Orange.
Ulangi setelah aku. Jeruk.
O, R...
J, E...
The fourth time she heard it,
Keempat kalinya dia mendengarnya,
she thought that it was because she was completely drained of energy.
dia pikir itu karena dia
Go around again!
Berkeliling lagi
Round and round!
Berputar-putar
But...
Tapi...
Now, she doesn't think being tired can explain what's been happening.
Kini dia tak berpikir lelah bisa menjelaskan apa yang terjadi.
-I'm talking about A. -So she has reality testing
- Ini tentang A. - Dia bisa mengetes kenyataan
capabilities and maintains proper ego boundaries?
dan mempertahankan batasan ego?
It's not like she has bipolar disorder either, right?
Dia tidak punya gangguan bipolar, bukan?
It's not an organic disorder or a feigned illness either?
Itu bukan gangguan organik atau penyakit palsu juga?
No.
Tidak.
The first things Patient A heard
Hal pertama yang didengar Pasien A bisa memberitahumu sesuatu.
"You ungrateful wench. You're such an ingrate."
"Wanita tak tahu terima kasih."
-And told you to have a conscience. -Yes.
- Menyuruhmu memiliki kesadaran. - Ya.
Could it be her sense of guilt?
Mungkin rasa bersalah?
Her sense of guilt?
Rasa bersalah?
She might be feeling guilty about ignoring someone in need.
Karena mengabaikan orang yang membutuhkan.
Sorry, but we don't have a place to go.
Maaf, kami tak punya tempat tujuan.
Please help us.
Bantu kami.
You said B, whom A met by chance,
Kau bilang B, yang kebetulan bertemu A,
-did her a big favor. -What?
- dia membantunya. - Apa?
You're one reckless woman.
Kau wanita yang ceroboh.
No!
Tidak!
Isn't it absurd that her sense of guilt is causing her to hear things?
Bukankah mustahil rasa bersalahnya menyebabkan dia mendengar sesuatu?
Wouldn't it depend on the person?
Tergantung orangnya.
Judging from what you told me, Patient A seems to be
Dari yang kau katakan, Pasien A tampaknya orang yang baik hati,
but has been trying to hide it.
tapi berusaha menyembunyikannya.
She might be a different person on the inside.
Hatinya mungkin berbeda.
She probably hates it that she is so compassionate,
Dia mungkin tidak suka kalau dia sangat penyayang
which causes her to intentionally behave in the opposite way.
yang menyebabkan dia sengaja berperilaku sebaliknya.
But the gap between her psyche and her actions must cause stress.
Tapi perbedaan antara jiwa dan tindakannya pasti menimbulkan stres.
There must be a reason why she hates her nature.
Pasti ada alasan kenapa dia membenci sifatnya.
Bad experiences in the past, for example.
Misalnya, pengalaman buruk masa lalu.
You said B, the homeless man, was even abandoned by his friend, C
Katamu B, gelandangan, bahkan ditinggalkan oleh temannya C
and has nowhere to go.
dan tak tahu harus ke mana.
What?
Apa?
Are you saying you saw Mura in this?
Maksudmu Tuan melihat Mura di sini?
-Yes. -You should have told me.
- Ya. - Seharusnya Tuan memberitahuku.
You were starving, and you know nothing.
Tuan kelaparan dan tak tahu apa-apa.
-If you keep acting on your own-- -Will you stop?
- Jika terus bertingkah sendiri... - Hentikan.
I can't believe something like this happened to Mura.
Aku tak percaya hal ini terjadi pada Mura.
I wonder what she's been through.
Apa yang dia alami?
How should we save her?
Bagaimana menyelamatkannya?
Lady Mura.
Nona Mura.
Can you hear me?
Kau bisa mendengarku?
Are you pulling my leg?
Apa kau bercanda?
Sorry?
Apa?
This is the cleverest thing humans have ever invented except cars.
Ini hal terpintar yang pernah diciptakan manusia, kecuali mobil.
I want to know what I saw.
Aku ingin tahu apa yang kulihat.
Give it back to me now.
Kembalikan padaku.
Do you want to see my skateboard tricks again?
Kau mau lihat trik skateboard-ku lagi?
No.
Tidak.
Why doesn't a grown-up have a cell phone?
Kenapa orang dewasa tak punya ponsel?
Being a grown-up doesn't mean having everything.
Dewasa tak berarti punya segalanya.
You're just a kid. It's none of your business.
Kau hanya anak-anak. Bukan urusanmu.
By the way, where did you get that?
Omong-omong, dari mana kau mendapat itu?
Are you signing up for the first time?
Kau mendaftar pertama kali?
For service providers, you can choose among LK, JT, and SG.
Untuk penyedia layanan, ada LK, JT, dan SG.
If you choose JT, you don't have to pay any start-up fees.
Jika pilih JT, tak perlu bayar biaya awal. Bisa pilih desain.
What is your budget range?
Berapa anggaranmu?
You can get a subsidy of 320,000 won.
Anda bisa dapat subsidi 320.000 won.
Depending on your data usage and the number of calls and texts,
Tergantung penggunaan data, panggilan, dan pesan,
your monthly bill will be around 50,000 won.
tagihan bulananmu sekitar 50.000 won.
You can also get 250 minutes of free calls,
Gratis 250 menit panggilan,
unlimited free texts, and 2G of LTE data.
pesan teks gratis tak terbatas, dan data LTE 2G.
You can play games and use search engines.
Bisa main gim dan pakai mesin pencari.
How long would you like your subscription to be?
Berapa lama berlangganan?
If you choose two years, you can pay your monthly bill
Jika dua tahun, Anda bisa bayar tagihan bulanan
plus the phone price in installments over 24 months.
ditambah harga ponsel dengan angsuran selama 24 bulan.
You can get a discount if a family member uses the same provider.
Ada diskon jika anggota keluarga pakai penyedia yang sama.
Under whose name would you like it to be?
Atas nama siapa ini?
Please give me your ID card. I'd like you to fill out this form.
Tolong berikan kartu identitasmu. Mohon isi formulir ini.
Here are some pens.
Silakan, ini penanya.
Phone service subscription form?
Formulir berlangganan layanan telepon?
Like this.
Seperti ini.
I think we need Ms. Descendant's help.
Kurasa kita perlu bantuan Nona Keturunan.
Help?
Bantuan?
Did I say "help"?
Apa aku bilang "bantuan"?
I think I said, "duty".
Kurasa aku bilang "tugas".
Mr. Nam!
Pak Nam!
Mr. Nam. We have customers.
Pak Nam. Ada pelanggan.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I have to work.
Aku harus kerja.
Don't go anywhere. Please stay here.
Jangan pergi. Tolong tetap di sini.
By the way,
Omong-omong...
where did you get those clothes?
dari mana kau dapat baju itu?
I found them in a recycling bin. Do you want some too?
Aku temukan di tempat sampah. Tuan mau?
Do you want to go back to being a fish again?
Kau mau kembali jadi ikan lagi?
Again? You just ate.
Lagi? Tuan baru saja makan.
You become hungry more often than I do.
Tuan lebih sering lapar daripada aku.
In my opinion, this is the best invention by humans.
Menurutku ini penemuan terbaik manusia.
They swell up in your stomach.
Itu mengembang di perutmu.
Be patient.
Bersabarlah.
I'll get some buns when I'm paid.
Aku akan beli roti saat dibayar.
-What happened to you? -It's your fault.
- Kau kenapa? - Ini salahmu.
It's my fault.
Ini salahku.
Is something wrong?
Ada masalah?
Well...
Kurasa...
I don't think I fulfilled my duties as a psychiatrist.
aku tak memenuhi tugasku sebagai psikiater. Jadi...
Are you okay?
Kau baik-baik saja?
Yes.
Ya.
I've been thinking about you.
Aku memikirkanmu.
Sorry?
Apa?
From when the sun rises in the east...
Dari saat matahari terbit di timur
until the sun sets in the west, all I think about...
sampai matahari terbenam di barat, aku hanya memikirkan...
is you.
dirimu.
Nothing could get you off my mind.
Tak ada yang bisa membuatku melupakanmu.
Why would you think about me?
Kenapa kau memikirkanku?
It's not like you're a bear.
Kau bukan beruang.
I just can't understand how you can be so clumsy and stupid.
Aku tak paham kenapa kau bisa begitu ceroboh dan bodoh.
Because I couldn't understand,
Karena aku tak paham,
I had to think about it all the time.
aku selalu memikirkannya.
I didn't want to, but I kept thinking about you.
Aku tak mau, tapi aku terus memikirkanmu.
It seems like your legs are stupid too.
Sepertinya kakimu juga bodoh.
I think I should go.
Aku harus pergi.
Let me get to the point.
Aku akan langsung ke intinya.
My professor is a great person.
Profesorku orang yang baik.
She's given so many people happiness and peace.
Dia memberi banyak orang kebahagiaan dan kedamaian.
It has nothing to do with me.
Tak ada kaitannya denganku.
I'm not capable of giving you those things.
- Aku tak mampu memberimu hal-hal itu. - Aku tak butuh itu.
I'll talk to my professor.
Aku akan bicara dengan profesorku.
-She can-- -I've learned many things here.
- Dia bisa... - Aku belajar banyak hal di sini.
One of them is that you become abnormal if you tell the truth.
Salah satunya, kau menjadi tak normal jika kau jujur.
If you say you're a divine servant,
Jika kau bilang kau pelayan dewa, apa kau dianggap normal?
No, that's not what it's about.
Bukan tentang itu.
See?
Paham?
I'm the only one who trusts you.
Hanya aku yang percaya padamu.
Do you think it's easy to win someone's trust?
Apa kau pikir mudah memenangkan kepercayaan seseorang?
How great is it to have someone who trusts you?
Bukankah hebat memiliki seseorang yang memercayaimu?
That's...
Itulah...
who you are.
dirimu.
Come to me if you change your mind.
Telepon aku bila kau berubah pikiran.
I've done enough.
Sudah cukup.
My conscience is fine. It sure is.
Hati nuraniku baik-baik saja. Itu pasti.
It feels so refreshing.
Menyegarkan.
If you don't accept me, you'll go through everything.
Jika kau tak menerimaku, kau akan celaka.
Do I really have to repeat myself?
Apa aku harus ulangi?
It feels so refreshing.
Rasanya sangat menyegarkan.
How refreshing it is.
Sangat menyegarkan.
It sure feels refreshing.
Rasanya menyegarkan.
The mites are making me itch.
Tungau membuatku gatal.
I feel great.
Aku merasa hebat.
-Gosh, I feel amazing. -I feel sticky. Give me a bath.
- Aku merasa luar biasa. - Aku merasa lengket. Mandikan aku.
I feel so relieved.
Aku sangat lega.
You dumped rotten milk on me the other day, didn't you?
Kau buang susu busuk padaku kemarin, 'kan?
I feel so refreshed!
Aku merasa segar.
I have sole control over my mind.
Hanya aku yang bisa mengendalikan pikiranku.
-What are you going to do? -Be quiet!
- Apa yang akan kau lakukan? - Diam!
What is it? What's wrong?
Ada apa? Ada apa?
-What's happening? -Woman, you have no conscience.
- Ada apa? - Wanita tak punya nurani.
I have a clear conscience.
Nuraniku bersih.
Doctor!
Dokter.
Shouldn't you have knocked? Get out.
Bukankah harusnya kau mengetuk pintu? Keluar.
Doctor, why are you getting so aggressive these days?
Dokter, kenapa kau makin agresif belakangan ini?
-What are you talking about? -You've become so impatient,
- Maksudmu? - Kau jadi tak sabar
and you yell at me all the time.
dan terus memarahiku.
You even talk to yourself. You need to get proper sleep.
Kau bahkan bicara sendiri. Kau harus tidur nyenyak.
What do you do at night instead of sleeping?
Apa yang kau lakukan di malam hari?
Do you watch porn or what?
Menonton film porno?
You said you're into Game of Thrones these days.
Kau suka Game of Thrones.
Are you sure it's not an erotic video with the same title?
Yakin itu bukan video erotis berjudul yang sama?
I need some rest.
Aku butuh istirahat.
What time is the next patient's appointment?
Pukul berapa pasien berikutnya?
"There's nothing, of course.
"Tidak ada, tentu saja.
Both your morning and afternoon are completely empty,
Jadwal pagi dan siangmu kosong,
so you can rest whenever you want."
istirahatlah kapan pun kau mau."
One more thing. Mr. Park Sang-cheol called again.
Satu lagi. Pak Park Sang-cheol menelepon lagi.
Gosh, whatever.
Masa bodoh.
What?
Apa?
Go ahead and talk all you want.
Silakan bicara semaumu.
Blabber away.
Mengoceh.
I have a completely clear conscience.
Hati nuraniku benar-benar bersih.
Fine dust? Yellow dust? What are they?
Debu halus? Debu kuning? Apa itu?
I have no idea because I've never experienced them.
Entahlah karena aku tak pernah tahu.
What's the problem? Have you run out of things to say?
Apa masalahnya? Kau kehabisan kata-kata?
Or are you sleeping now?
Atau apa kau tidur?
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH DOCTOR YUN SO-A
KLINIK JIWA BLESSED DOKTER YUN SO-A
What am I doing now?
Sekarang apa yang kulakukan?
I must be going crazy.
Aku pasti sudah gila.
If you don't accept me, you'll go through everything.
Jika kau tak menerimaku, kau akan celaka.
This is complete nonsense.
Ini tak masuk akal.
SO-A
SO-A
-What's up, So-a? -Hey, there's a guy.
- Ada apa, So-a? - Hai, pria itu.
-Is this an update on A's story? -No.
- Apa ini cerita baru tentang A? - Tidak.
Is he handsome?
Apa dia tampan?
Yes. I mean, no.
Ya. Maksudku, tidak.
-Whom does he look like? -Jude Law?
- Dia mirip siapa? - Jude Law?
No, I was just kidding.
Tidak, aku bercanda.
I guess he's the sexy type. Is he rich?
Kurasa dia tipe seksi. Dia kaya?
I don't think so.
Kurasa tidak.
Hey, stop talking. Just listen.
Berhentilah bicara. Dengarkan saja.
Go ahead.
Silakan.
Every time I see him, he says weird things to me.
Tiap kali bertemu, dia katakan hal aneh.
Like what?
Seperti apa?
In those scary paranormal dramas,
Dalam drama paranormal yang menakutkan itu,
you see people encountering monks or mountain deities
kau melihat orang-orang bertemu biksu atau dewa gunung,
-who randomly threaten them. -You mean, like a curse?
- yang mengancam mereka. - Maksudmu kutukan?
Well, not exactly a curse. But something like that.
Bukan kutukan. Tapi sesuatu seperti itu.
When you don't do as they say,
Jika tak melakukan permintaan mereka,
the curse continues to haunt you. You know those movies, right?
kutukan itu terus menghantuimu. Kau tahu, bukan?
Can things like that actually happen in real life?
Apa hal seperti itu bisa terjadi di kehidupan nyata?
Did I seriously just say that? What am I saying right now?
Apa aku serius mengatakan itu? Apa-apaan ini?
I'm sorry. I have to go.
Maaf. Aku harus pergi.
Take a picture.
Ambil foto.
I guess I'm extremely exhausted these days.
Kurasa aku sangat lelah.
QUACK
KWEK
My gosh. Why did she take a photo like this?
Astaga.
NURSE YU
PERAWAT YU
What's going on? Where are you?
Ada apa? Di mana kau?
I'm just outside your door,
Aku di luar pintumu,
but I can't go in because I'm so scared of you.
tapi aku tak bisa masuk karena takut padamu.
Mr. Ma's appointments are booked on every Thursday.
Janji temu Pak Ma dipesan tiap hari Kamis.
Mr. Park Sang-cheol called again saying he wants an appointment,
Pak Park Sang-cheol menelepon ingin bertemu,
but I talked him out of it.
tapi kubujuk dia.
There are other updates too.
Ada berita lain juga.
What are they?
Apa itu?
Shall I start with good news or bad news?
Mulai dengan kabar baik atau buruk?
Just say it.
Katakan saja.
There's no update on the diamond thief.
Tidak ada kabar baru pencuri itu.
The bank called to let you know that you can't switch
Bank memberi tahu kau tak bisa beralih
to the loan with seven percent interest.
ke pinjaman dengan bunga 7%.
The windshields will be covered by insurance, but the premium will go up.
Pembersih kaca ditanggung asuransi, tapi preminya naik.
Also, the landlord said we can renew the contract
Kata pemilik, bisa teruskan kontrak
at a higher rent if we can't pay more for the deposit.
tapi sewa naik jika deposit tak naik.
-All right. What's the good news? -I just told you.
- Apa kabar baiknya? - Sudah kubilang.
What? What did you say?
Apa? Apa katamu?
The landlord is okay with us not paying more for the deposit.
Tak apa-apa jika tak bisa bayar lebih untuk deposit.
He'll raise our rent instead.
Dia akan menaikkan sewa.
What is this?
Apa ini?
This could be a solution to our problem.
Ini solusi untuk masalah kita.
It's today.
Hari ini.
SEUN UNIVERSITY ALUMNI REUNION
REUNI ALUMNI UNIVERSITAS SEUN
Everyone there must be pretty influential.
Mereka semua pasti sangat berpengaruh.
You should ask them for help.
Kau harusnya minta tolong.
I can't do it even if I wanted to as I don't know anyone influential.
Aku tak bisa meski ingin karena tak kenal orang berpengaruh.
Why should I go there?
Kenapa aku harus ke sana?
Go ahead and leave me!
Tinggalkan saja aku!
Get out of my life, you jerk!
Keluar dari hidupku, Berengsek.
I turned that clueless guy...
Aku mengubah pria bodoh itu
into a decent man by feeding him good food
jadi pria baik dengan memberinya makan dan membelikannya pakaian mahal.
How can he dump me?
Teganya dia mencampakkanku?
-Fried chicken is... -I can't believe he two-timed me.
- Ayam goreng... - Aku tak percaya dia selingkuh.
I need 4,000 won more.
Aku butuh 4.000 won lagi.
-She's just a friend? -I need two more customers.
- Dia hanya teman? - Aku butuh dua pelanggan lagi.
How dare you!
Beraninya kau!
Don't get killed in an accident. I hope you live a great life.
Jangan sampai terbunuh dalam kecelakaan. Semoga hidupmu indah.
-You jerk... -Is that a lump of gold?
- Kau berengsek... - Itu bongkahan emas?
-Gold? -It's a big lump of gold.
- Emas? - Itu bongkahan besar emas.
It's very big and tall.
Sangat besar dan tinggi.
No one will know even if we cut out and take a corner of it.
Tak ada yang tahu jika kita ambil secuil.
Are you talking about that thing, by any chance?
Apa kau membicarakan hal itu?
We've been here for a while. I can't believe you noticed it just now.
Kita sudah agak lama di sini. Aku tak percaya kau baru sadar.
When I saw it, I thought that humans must really love gold.
Saat kulihat, kupikir manusia pasti sangat suka emas.
At first, I thought it was a temple.
Awalnya kukira itu kuil.
However, I've never seen a god that has a temple like that
Namun aku belum pernah melihat dewa dengan kuil seperti ini
anywhere in the Land of the Sky, Land of Earth, and Land of Water.
di Negeri Langit, Negeri Tanah, atau Negeri Air.
Here, gold is like a god.
Di sini, emas seperti dewa.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Hang in there for just a bit longer.
Bertahanlah sebentar lagi.
I'll regain my power soon. That's what my gut is telling me.
Aku segera dapatkan kembali kekuatanku. Itu intuisiku.
When that happens, the first thing I'll do is make the gold you lost.
Hal pertama yang kulakukan membuat emasmu yang hilang.
Namsuri.
Namsuri.
I know why you're turning into an idiot.
Aku tahu kenapa kau berubah jadi idiot.
I can live without much difficulty, even in this situation,
Aku bisa hidup tanpa kesulitan bahkan dalam situasi ini
thanks to your dedication. I know that, of course.
berkat dedikasimu. Aku tahu itu, tentu saja.
You didn't actually think I'd say that, did you?
Pikirmu aku akan mengatakannya?
Mura...
Mura…
It's Mura.
Itu Mura.
Namsuri.
Namsuri.
-Namsuri! -Yes!
- Namsuri! - Ya!
-Mura is over there. -Pardon me?
- Mura di sana. - Apa?
-Where? -Over there!
- Di mana? - Di sana!
Where?
Di mana?
SEUN UNIVERSITY ALUMNI REUNION
REUNI ALUMNI UNIVERSITAS
Hey,
Hai...
are you really not coming?
kau tak datang?
Why should I go there?
Kenapa aku ke sana?
All of them will treat me like an oddball.
Semua akan anggap aku eksentrik.
It won't be any better for me. Why am I attending this thing?
Sama saja denganku. Kenapa aku datang?
Oh, right. I'm here because I need money.
Ya. Aku kemari karena butuh uang.
How much do you need? I can lend you one or two million.
Berapa? Aku bisa pinjamkan satu atau dua juta.
Forget it. Just buy yourself some candy with it.
Lupakan. Tidak usah.
Today is a good day for you. Cheer up.
Ini hari yang baik. Cerialah.
I see that luck is coming your way.
Kulihat keberuntunganmu akan datang.
All right. You have such great instincts.
Baiklah. Kau punya naluri yang hebat.
Gosh, seriously.
Astaga, serius.
It could've been at the school's assembly hall.
Bisa di aula pertemuan sekolah.
Why did they have to pick this hotel on a hill? Darn it.
Kenapa mereka memilih hotel di bukit? Sial.
You're turning into a foul mouth.
Mulutmu jadi kotor.
Why don't you try walking up this hill in high heels?
Kenapa kau tak menaiki bukit ini dengan sepatu hak tinggi?
I dressed up because I heard people are nicer to you when you look nice.
Karena orang lebih baik padamu saat kau terlihat cantik.
Hey, I've run out of oxygen.
Aku kehabisan napas.
Wait. If you see Shin Ja-ya today, you should avoid her.
Tunggu. Jika kau melihat Shin Ja-ya, hindari dia.
Gosh, my feet are killing me.
Astaga, kakiku sakit.
Why did they have to pick this hotel? This is ridiculous.
Kenapa mereka harus memilih hotel ini? Ini konyol.
Ms. Yun.
Nona Yun?
Unbelievable.
Sulit dipercaya.
Just a second, please.
Tunggu.
I'm going up there too.
Aku juga ke sana.
If I offer you a ride because it's on my way anyway,
Jika aku menawarkan tumpangan karena kita sejalan,
would you tell me to mind my business again?
- akankah kau mengusirku? - Ya.
-Well, I mean-- -I see.
- Maksudku... - Begitu.
I knew you'd say that.
Sudah kuduga.
Wait, that's not what I meant.
Tunggu, bukan itu maksudku.
He must be doing that on purpose.
Dia pasti sengaja melakukannya.
I think he's trying to provoke me.
Kurasa dia mencoba memancingku.
If you don't accept me, you'll go through everything.
Jika kau tak menerimaku, kau akan celaka.
Excuse me, sir.
Permisi, Pak.
Yes?
Ya?
Some people say the opposite of what they feel.
Beberapa orang mengatakan kebalikan perasaan mereka.
-Pardon? -For example,
- Apa? - Misalnya,
their "It's fine" means "It isn't fine."
"Tidak apa-apa," artinya, "Tidak baik."
"I don't want it" means "I do want it."
"Aku tak mau," berarti, "Aku mau."
"I'm fine" means "Please help."
"Aku tak apa-apa," berarti, "Tolong bantu."
Really?
Sungguh?
Then that doctor...
Lalu dokter itu…
Not her.
Bukan dia.
She seems very sure of her feelings.
Dia tampak tegas dengan perasaannya.
I thought you had given up.
Kukira Tuan sudah menyerah.
I had.
Ya.
But she begged for forgiveness and pleaded that I come.
Tapi dia memohon ampun dan memohon aku datang.
-When? -A few days ago.
- Kapan? - Beberapa hari lalu.
Come to me if you change your mind.
Telepon aku bila kau berubah pikiran.
Has she been awakened then?
Dia sadar saat itu?
No.
Tidak.
I think she was moved by me.
Kurasa dia tersentuh olehku.
I'm the only one who trusts you.
Hanya aku yang percaya padamu.
How great is it to have someone who trusts you?
Bukankah hebat memiliki seseorang
That's...
Itulah...
who you are.
dirimu.
-Open the door. -Yes, My Lord.
- Buka pintunya. - Ya, Tuan.
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH CLINIC
KLINIK JIWA BLESSED
What?
Apa?
They're closed today.
Mereka tutup hari ini.
Nurse Yu. The doctor isn't coming back today, right?
Perawat Yu. Dokter tak akan kembali hari ini, bukan?
No. She went to her college reunion.
Tidak. Dia pergi ke reuni kampus.
She'll be back late. Why?
Dia pulang larut malam. Kenapa?
Do you want to see the nurse?
Ingin bertemu perawatnya?
He's working at my store right now.
Dia kerja di tokoku sekarang.
It's okay.
Tidak usah.
It feels nice to visit the school once in a while.
Rasanya senang mengunjungi sekolah sesekali.
What school? It's at Grand Park Hotel.
Sekolah apa? Ini Grand Park Hotel.
They're all rich.
Mereka semua kaya.
Should we come back tomorrow?
Kita kembali besok?
Let's go.
Ayo.
The bus goes there too. Why must we always take expensive taxis?
Bus ke sana juga.
We live day-to-day.
Kita hidup hari demi hari.
We can't survive like this.
Kita tak bisa bertahan seperti ini.
So-a.
So-a.
-Hi, Ji-won. -Hi.
- Hai, Ji-won. - Hai.
What's gotten into you?
Ada apa denganmu?
You never come to reunions or gatherings.
Kau tak pernah menghadiri reuni atau pertemuan.
That's true.
Benar.
I just felt like coming.
Aku hanya ingin datang.
How are things?
Apa kabar?
Rumor has it your clinic is struggling.
Katanya klinikmu sedang buruk.
-Stop it. -Yes.
- Hentikan. - Ya.
What's with the flowers?
Bunga ini untuk apa?
I have to show my appreciation to a donor
Aku harus tunjukkan penghargaan kepada donatur
for their donation to our hospital.
atas sumbangan mereka ke rumah sakit kami.
It's the hospital director's orders.
Perintah direktur rumah sakit.
Really?
Sungguh?
Who is it that the director sent flowers?
Untuk siapa direktur mengirim bunga?
He's the biggest individual donor among alums.
Dia donor individu terbesar di antara para alumni.
Every year too.
Setiap tahun.
He donates a lot and helps people in need a lot too.
Dia menyumbang banyak dan membantu orang yang sangat membutuhkan.
He's been supporting young entrepreneurs since last year.
Dia mendukung pengusaha muda sejak tahun lalu.
I hear he's doing it all personally.
Kudengar dia lakukan semuanya sendiri.
Young entrepreneurs?
Pengusaha muda?
Darn it.
Sial.
Perfect, right? He's two years older and majored in business management.
Sempurna, 'kan? Dua tahun lebih tua, jurusan manajemen bisnis.
He was there for one year and transferred to Yale.
Dia di sana setahun lalu pindah ke Yale.
He came back and graduated early after a year and a half.
Dia kembali dan lulus lebih awal 1,5 tahun.
It is awkward for both sides to act like alumni.
Sangat canggung jika keduanya bersikap seperti alumni.
He isn't close to any alum either.
Dia juga tak dekat dengan yang lain. Kudengar dia sangat tertutup.
He's single too.
Dia juga lajang.
His face, body, and heart. They all sparkle.
Wajah, tubuh, dan hatinya. Semuanya berkilauan.
Maybe he's a complete fake.
Mungkin dia orang yang palsu.
No way. Not him.
Tak mungkin. Bukan dia.
No?
Tidak?
Would you be able to say this to someone's face?
Apa kau bisa mengatakan ini langsung?
"Instead of bothering the bank staff regarding your interest rate,
"Daripada mengganggu staf bank soal tingkat bungamu,
you should work harder to earn money on your own."
bekerjalah lebih keras untuk mencari uang sendiri."
Could you?
Apa kau bisa?
What?
Apa?
The devil is in the details.
Setan ada pada detailnya.
People like that are the ones
Orang seperti itu adalah orang yang
who'd insist on getting you to pay for windshield wipers.
bersikeras membuatmu membayar untuk pembersih kaca depan.
They're numb to others' pain.
Mereka tak paham rasa sakit orang lain.
Who knows? That may be a mask.
Siapa yang tahu? Itu mungkin topeng.
Do you know him personally?
Apa kau mengenalnya secara pribadi?
How would she know him?
Mana mungkin dia mengenalnya?
Your clinic really must be struggling.
Klinikmu pasti sedang sulit.
I mean, you're all twisted inside.
Maksudku hatimu busuk.
-Hey, stop. -Hey, Hee-young.
- Hai, hentikan. - Hai.
Are you talking behind my back?
Apa kau bicara di belakangku?
Ms. Yun. Are your feet okay?
Nona Yun, apa kakimu baik-baik saja?
Do you know each other?
Kalian saling kenal?
Yes. We know each other well enough to talk...
Ya. Kami cukup kenal satu sama lain untuk bicara
behind the other's back.
di belakang yang lain.
She's a bank VIP, so we discuss our interest rates openly.
Dia VIP di bank, kami bahas tingkat bunga secara terbuka.
-VIP?
- VIP?
She broke my windshield wipers by mistake.
Dia  tak sengaja merusak pembersih kacaku.
I don't care about her reimbursing me,
Aku tak permasalahkan itu,
but she can't rest until she pays for it.
tapi dia tak bisa tenang sampai membayarnya.
That's our relationship.
Itu hubungan kami.
-That's your relationship.
- Itu hubunganmu.
What was that? Were you playing the knight in shining armor?
Apa itu? Apa kau berperan jadi kesatria gagah?
I didn't know you were an alum.
Aku tak tahu kau alumni.
-Had I known-- -If you had, what?
- Andai aku tahu... - Lalu?
-You'd lend me money? -Sorry?
- Mau meminjamkan uang? - Apa?
Are you insane?
Apa kau gila?
Sorry.
Maaf.
I'm drunk.
Aku mabuk.
I jumped straight to the point without thinking.
Aku langsung ke intinya tanpa berpikir.
Did you come here to borrow money?
Apa kau kemari untuk meminjam uang?
You're very unique.
Kau sangat unik.
It's common courtesy not to ask that, even if you think it.
Sudah umum tak meminta itu, bahkan jika kau pikirkan.
Yes. I'm going to start asking around once I sober up.
Ya. Aku akan mulai bertanya setelah aku sadar.
-Why did you follow me out? -I did not.
- Kenapa kau mengikutiku? - Tidak.
I have somewhere else to be.
Aku harus pergi.
-Is that Ja-ya? -No one else compares.
- Apa itu Ja-ya? - Pastinya.
-Ja-ya. -You look pretty.
- Ja-ya. - Kau cantik.
-Hi.
- Hai.
-You made it. -Hello.
- Kau datang. - Halo.
-Hi. -You look so pretty.
- Hai. - Kau sangat cantik.
-How have you been? -Why are you so late?
- Apa kabar? - Kenapa kau terlambat?
I'll get going now.
Aku pergi. Ada orang yang tak ingin kutemui.
Same goes for me. Good day.
Aku pun begitu. Salam.
You look so pretty.
Kau sangat cantik.
Look who's here.
Lihat siapa ini.
-Hi-- -Look who's here.
- Hai... - Lihat siapa ini.
It's the Three-Second Beauty from Seun Medical School.
Keindahan Tiga Detik dari Sekolah Kedokteran Seun.
I gave her that nickname.
Itu panggilan dariku.
-It's the Three-second Beauty. -She may seem like a beauty,
- Keindahan Tiga Detik. - Dia mungkin cantik,
but after three seconds, you realize she's just a beggar.
tapi setelah itu, kau sadar dia hanya pengemis.
I gave her that nickname.
Itu.panggilan dariku.
She may look like a beauty, but after three seconds, you realize...
Dia mungkin cantik. Setelah itu,
-Oh my. -...she's just a beggar.
- Astaga. - kau sadar dia pengemis.
Look at her.
Lihat dia.
Are you scowling at my roses?
Apa kau merengut pada mawarku?
-No. -Yes, you are.
- Tidak. - Ya, benar.
Are you scowling...
Apa kau merengut...
-You're jealous because I got this... -...at my roses?
- Kau cemburu karena kudapat ini... - pada mawarku?
-...from a fan. -Yes, you are.
- dari penggemar. - Ya, benar.
-Ja-ya. -You're jealous because...
- Ja-ya. - Kau cemburu karena...
-You still can't pronounce properly? -...I got this from a fan.
- Kau masih tak bisa mengeja? - dari penggemar.
You still can't pronounce your words properly?
Kau masih tak bisa mengeja dengan benar?
I see you talk like that on TV at times too.
Aku melihatmu berbicara seperti itu di TV.
Don't do that, baby.
Jangan, Sayang.
And stop using our school name.
Hentikan menyebut sekolah kita.
Why, you...
Kenapa kau…
Say my name properly.
Ucapkan namaku dengan benar.
I did. Shin Ja-ya.
Sudah. Shin Ja-ya.
-Say my name properly. -Shin Ja-ya!
- Ucapkan namaku. - Shin Ja-ya!
Shin Ja-ya.
Shin Ja-ya.
Shin Ja-ya?
Shin Ja-ya?
Don't be like that.
Jangan begitu.
Later. It was good seeing you.
Sampai nanti. Senang bertemu.
-That's so funny. -Is that really her name?
- Itu sangat lucu. - Itu sungguh namanya?
Is your dad...
Apa ayahmu...
not back yet?
belum kembali?
-Is your dad not back yet? -You know, your dad who went to volunteer
- Apa ayahmu belum kembali? - Kau tahu ayahmu jadi sukarelawan
in Somalia or somewhere ridiculous
di Somalia atau di tempat lain
-and never came back. -In Somalia or somewhere...
- dan tak pernah kembali. - Di Somalia...
Guys, do you know how great a person her dad is?
Apa kalian tahu betapa hebat ayahnya?
He used to bring in all the homeless and orphans from the streets,
Dia biasa mengumpulkan semua tunawisma dan yatim piatu dari jalanan
-feed them, wash them, -Do you know...
- beri makan, mandikan, - Kau tahu...
-dress them, and teach them. -...how great a person her dad is?
- beri baju dan ajari mereka. - ayahnya hebat?
-He was a real angel. -Dress them, feed them,
- Dia benar-benar malaikat. - Beri baju, beri makan...
-and teach them. -An angel without wings.
- dan ajari mereka. - Malaikat tanpa sayap.
He was a real angel.
Dia benar-benar malaikat.
-I think she was a junior in high school. -An angel without wings.
- Saat dia kelas 1 SMA. - Malaikat tanpa sayap.
There was an earthquake somewhere in Africa,
Ada gempa di daerah Afrika,
so he left to go volunteer.
dia pergi jadi relawan.
I think she was a junior in high school.
Saat dia kelas 1 SMA.
We went to the same junior high and high school, so I know her well.
Kami sekolah di SMP dan SMA yang sama. Aku mengenalnya dengan baik.
What a great man.
Pria yang hebat.
-We went to the same... -A great man?
- Kami satu sekolah... - Pria hebat?
...junior high and high school.
sewaktu SMP dan SMA.
Yes, he was a great man.
Benar, dia pria yang hebat.
He had such conviction...
Dia memiliki keyakinan
that he sacrificed his family
untuk mengorbankan keluarganya
-for the greater good of mankind. -Yes, he was a great man.
- demi umat manusia. - Dia pria hebat.
He had such conviction that he sacrificed his family
Dia memiliki keyakinan mengorbankan keluarganya demi umat manusia.
What?
Apa?
You. Stop talking!
Kau. Berhenti bicara!
Why would she do that to the flowers?
Kenapa bunganya?
Hey. Give me my flowers!
Hai. Berikan bungaku!
She ripped her blouse.
Dia merobek blusnya.
-Why would she do that? -Oh, no.
- Kenapa dia melakukan itu? - Tidak.
Are you done?
Sudah selesai?
Let me talk now.
Biar aku bicara.
Tell the others that I left.
Beri tahu yang lain aku pulang.
Fine, I understand that goodwill is ridiculed these days.
Aku mengerti niat baik ditertawakan belakangan ini.
But you didn't have to confirm it with your pretty lips.
Tapi kau tak perlu memastikannya dengan bibirmu yang cantik.
Even if you don't possess virtues,
Bahkan jika kau tak punya kebaikan,
you should at least try to look like you do.
terlihatlah memilikinya.
You should try to spend less time on social media.
Sebaiknya kurangi waktu di media sosial.
You're obsessed with attention.
Kau terobsesi dengan perhatian.
There was this term that is used on social media.
Ada istilah yang digunakan di media sosial.
An attention seeker.
Pencari perhatian.
It doesn't have very nice connotations, though.
Tapi artinya tak ada yang baik.
I'm really leaving now.
Aku pergi sekarang.
What? An attention seeker?
Apa? Pencari perhatian?
How dare you?
Beraninya kau?
Stop right there!
Berhenti!
-That's enough. -Get out of my way.
- Cukup. - Minggir.
Hey, So-a. Stop right there.
Hai, So-tae. Berhenti.
Let's go.
Ayo.
Guys. Do you know how great a person her dad is?
Apa kalian tahu betapa hebat ayahnya?
He used to bring in all the homeless and orphans from the streets,
Dia biasa mengumpulkan semua tunawisma dan yatim piatu dari jalanan
feed them, wash them,
beri makan, mandikan,
dress them, and teach them.
beri baju dan mengajari mereka.
How dare you call me an attention seeker? Stop right there!
Beraninya kau menyebutku pencari perhatian? Berhenti!
You little--
Dasar kau...
What?
Apa?
What are you doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
-Who are you? -What is your last name?
- Siapa kau? - Apa nama belakangmu?
Is it Shim?
Apakah Shim?
You don't know who I am?
Kau tak kenal aku?
It's me.
Ini aku.
You look like someone I know whose last name is Shim.
Kau mirip kenalanku yang nama keluarganya Shim.
She's stuck-up and obnoxious.
Dia kacau dan menjijikkan.
Her last name is Shim.
Nama keluarganya Shim.
Are you...
Apa kau...
What are you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
Gosh.
Astaga.
By the way,
Omong-omong,
why are you following my woman around and bothering her?
kenapa kau mengikutiku wanitaku dan mengganggunya?
What? Your woman?
Apa? Wanitamu?
Yes,
Ya.
she belongs to me.
Dia milikku.
Ask for my permission if you want to bother her.
Minta izinku jika mau mengganggunya.
Isn't that Ja-ya?
Bukankah itu Ja-ya?
-It's Ja-ya. -It is her.
- Itu Ja-ya. - Itu dia.
So her last name is Ja?
Jadi, nama keluarganya Ja?
I'm glad it's not Shim.
Untung bukan Shim.
Why...
Kenapa...
are you here?
kau di sini?
I took a taxi.
Aku naik taksi.
The flowers...
Bunga-bunganya...
didn't stop babbling.
tak berhenti mengoceh.
It's driving me crazy.
Itu membuatku gila.
I've warned you.
Aku sudah peringatkan.
-Taxi. -What?
- Taksi. - Apa?
Get in.
Masuk.
That night, I ran recklessly.
Malam itu, aku berlari serampangan.
It wasn't to catch my dad who abandoned us.
Bukan untuk menangkap ayahku yang menelantarkan kami.
It was to, instead of showing my pain,
Bukannya menunjukkan rasa sakitku,
gain the energy to live on.
tapi untuk mendapatkan energi untuk hidup.
As always,
Seperti biasa,
my dad would go his own way.
ayahku akan pergi sendiri.
I would have to rely on myself.
Aku harus mengandalkan diriku sendiri.
I realized this fact that night.
Aku samar-samar menyadarinya malam itu.
I tried to capture all the pain I felt in my whole body.
Aku mencoba menangkap semua rasa sakit yang kurasakan di seluruh tubuhku.
I told myself it was all my dad's fault.
Aku bilang itu semua salah ayahku.
I decided to live on that hatred and resentment from then on.
Aku memutuskan hidup dari kebencian itu mulai saat itu.
I ran to let my dad go.
Aku berlari untuk melepaskan ayahku.
It was my last resort.
Itu pilihan terakhirku.
UNDYING CONNECTION BETWEEN PARENTS AND CHILDREN
HUBUNGAN ORANG TUA DAN ANAK SELAMANYA
Why did you bring me here?
Mengapa kau membawaku kemari?
You won't let me know where you live. So I brought you to where I live.
Kau tak katakan di mana rumahmu. Jadi, kubawa ke rumahku.
You can tell me where you live if you want.
Beri tahu aku di mana rumahmu jika mau.
Thank you for the jacket.
Terima kasih jaketnya.
Where are you going?
Kau mau ke mana?
You've received a god's help many times. How can you just leave every time?
Kau sering dapat bantuan dewa. Kok bisa pergi begitu saja?
What do humans call it again?
Manusia menyebutnya apa?
-An ingrate. -Exactly.
- Tak tahu terima kasih. - Tepat.
Are you an ingrate?
Apa kau tak tahu terima kasih?
I'll work and pay the bills.
Aku akan bekerja dan membayar tagihan.
Mura will pay me later.
Mura akan membayarku nanti.
-Next. -I have to work.
- Berikutnya. - Aku harus bekerja.
It's an electronic notice board.
Itu papan pengumuman elektronik.
It was probably a news program.
Mungkin itu program berita.
Maybe the person happened to be caught on camera on the street
Mungkin orang itu tertangkap kamera di jalan
or was interviewed.
atau diwawancarai.
Are you sure you can recognize the person?
Kau yakin bisa mengenali orang itu?
I would recognize my dear Mura even with my eyes closed.
Aku mengenal Mura kesayanganku bahkan dengan mata tertutup.
-So it's a girl. -She's a goddess.
- Jadi, dia wanita. - Dia dewi.
If there are no electronic notice boards in your world, what is there?
Jika tak ada papan pengumuman elektronik di duniamu, apa yang ada?
Water, wind, trees, the sky,
Air, angin, pohon, langit...
mountains,
gunung...
fish, air, and birds.
ikan, udara, dan burung.
Is that all?
Itu saja?
You said it's a world of deities. We have those here too.
Kau bilang itu dunia para dewa. Kami punya itu juga.
Those you have here are all fake.
Semua yang ada di sini palsu.
It's such a relief that the world of humans
Sungguh melegakan dunia manusia tak termasuk dalam dunia dewa.
To think the deities' world would've ended up like this...
Jika dunia para dewa seperti ini…
All right.
Baiklah.
-You can hold my arm. -Sorry?
- Kau bisa pegang lenganku. - Maaf?
I'm fine.
Aku baik-baik saja.
and duty.
dan tugasnya.
You still don't see her?
Kau masih belum melihatnya?
That thing is visually so distracting.
Itu sangat mengganggu penglihatan.
The more distracted people are, the better products sell.
Semakin mengganggu, produk yang lebih baik laku.
I wish you were actually a god.
Kuharap kau benar-benar dewa.
Don't they have the power to make anything happen?
Bukankah dewa punya kuasa untuk mewujudkan apa pun?
Can you make that become mine?
Bisakah kau membuatnya jadi milikku?
If you faithfully carry out your duties as my servant,
Jika kau setia bertugas sebagai pelayanku,
I can certainly make that thing for you.
aku pasti bisa membuat itu untukmu.
You can make it?
Kau bisa membuatnya?
-That too? -Yes.
- Itu juga? - Ya.
All I need to do is snap my fingers.
Aku hanya perlu menjentikkan jari.
Then can you make that too?
Bisa kau buat itu juga?
-Sure thing. -Then how about that bridge?
- Tentu. - Bagaimana dengan jembatan itu?
Of course.
Tentu saja.
What about the river?
Kalau sungai?
That's a piece of cake.
Itu mudah sekali.
Then what about that tree?
Kalau pohon itu?
I can even make gold for you.
Aku bahkan bisa membuat emas untukmu.
Gold?
Emas?
Gosh, my heart is racing.
Jantungku berdetak kencang.
I want to become richer than Sheikh Mansour.
Aku mau lebih kaya dari Syekh Mansour.
-Make me some gold now. -Right now, I can't.
- Buat sekarang. - Saat ini tak bisa.
I told you I'm in a bit of a situation.
Kubilang aku sedang kesulitan.
Right.
Benar.
There she is.
Itu dia.
I see her.
Aku melihatnya.
You do?
Benarkah?
That woman?
Wanita itu?
I told you that she's a goddess.
Kubilang dia adalah dewi.
Well,
Kurasa...
I guess you can call her a goddess.
kau bisa menyebutnya dewi.
She's Hye-ra, a famous actress who is known for her divine beauty.
Dia Hye-ra, aktris terkenal karena kecantikannya.
Hye-ra?
Hye-ra?
I guess that's her name here.
Kurasa itu namanya di sini.
Everyone worships her beauty.
Semua memuja kecantikannya.
You're not the only one who thinks that.
- Bukan hanya kau yang berpikir begitu. - Kau benar. Dia jelas bersinar.
She has this presence about her that can't be hidden.
Kehadirannya tak bisa disembunyikan.
Right. Think about it, though.
Benar. Pikirkan itu.
Will someone who's so extraordinary
Akankah seseorang yang begitu hebat
be willing to meet you?
bersedia bertemu denganmu?
Don't you worry.
Jangan khawatir.
I'm her lord and her king.
Aku junjungannya dan rajanya.
Well...
Itu...
If you take me to that castle where Mura is,
Jika kau bawa aku ke tempat Mura berada,
your duty will be fulfilled.
tugasmu akan terpenuhi.
It means that you'll no longer have to live as my servant.
Artinya kau tak lagi hidup sebagai pelayanku.
You still don't want to do it?
Masih tak mau?
I'm here. I'm actually here.
Aku di sini. Aku sungguh di sini!
What should I do now?
Aku harus bagaimana?
I wish Namsuri was here.
Kuharap Namsuri ada di sini.
It's too bad he had to work.
Sayang dia harus bekerja.
Can I really be doing this?
Bolehkah aku melakukan ini?
Gosh, is this okay?
Astaga, apa ini tak apa?
Thanks for your help. You could've been a better servant,
Terima kasih. Kau bisa jadi pelayan lebih baik.
but Mura will bestow a great award upon you for what you did today.
Mura akan beri hadiah besar atas perbuatanmu ini.
When my situation improves,
Saat situasiku membaik,
I'll also give you everything you mentioned yesterday.
akan kuberikan semua yang kau katakan kemarin.
You may leave.
Kau boleh pergi.
Hold on a second.
Tunggu sebentar.
-Well... do you really have to go? -You still don't believe me, do you?
Ya. Haruskah kau pergi?
I want to show you what will happen in there,
Aku ingin tunjukkan apa yang terjadi,
but Mura hates humans as much as I do, especially women.
tapi Mura benci manusia, terutama wanita.
I'm doing this for your sake. You should leave.
Ini demi dirimu. Pergilah.
Wait, hold on. That's not what I meant.
Tunggu. Bukan itu maksudku.
This isn't Hye-ra's place.
Ini bukan tempat Hye-ra.
It's not her place, but...
Bukan tempatnya, tapi…
Yes.
Ya.
You need a reality check.
Kau butuh pemeriksaan realitas.
He told me to leave.
Dia menyuruhku pergi.
I did my best. Conscience?
Aku melakukan yang terbaik. Hati nurani?
There's nothing wrong with my conscience. Stop saying weird things.
Nuraniku tak bermasalah. Stop katakan hal aneh.
What? Come to think of it, I haven't been hearing those sounds.
Apa? Kalau dipikir-pikir, aku belum mendengar suara itu.
Great. My conscience has been restored. Perfect.
Bagus. Kesadaranku sudah pulih. Sempurna.
I should get going.
Aku harus pergi.
Gosh, no!
Astaga, tidak.
I can't leave.
Aku tak bisa pergi.
I guess that car broke down.
Kurasa mobil itu rusak.
It's that doctor.
Dia dokter itu.
What is wrong with me?
Ada apa denganku?
Why on earth can't I leave?
Kenapa aku tak bisa pergi?
Her place is pretty nice.
Tempatnya cukup bagus.
I should take a warm bath first.
Aku harus mandi air hangat dulu.
I'm hungry too. No, that's impossible.
Aku juga lapar. Itu tidak mungkin.
Her servants are well trained.
Pelayannya terlatih.
Sir, are you looking for someone? I'll help you.
Pak, kau mencari seseorang? Aku akan membantumu.
I can find her myself.
Akan kucari sendiri.
I want to surprise her.
Aku mau memberinya kejutan.
Sure, have a great time.
Tentu, selamat mencari.
What was that about? Why did he talk to me so casually?
Kenapa dia bicara padaku biasa saja?
She must be close by.
Dia pasti dekat.
I can feel it.
Aku bisa merasakannya.
You're not sick, and you're probably not here to see me either.
Kau tidak sakit dan kau mungkin tak mau menemuiku.
Why would I come all the way here to see you?
Kenapa aku kemari untuk menemuimu?
You're right.
Kau benar.
I got the wrong idea and overreacted.
Aku salah paham dan berlebihan.
But why are you gushing out exhaust fumes in front of my hotel?
Tapi kenapa kau mengeluarkan asap knalpot di depan hotelku?
That I want to know.
Aku ingin tahu.
Why are you saying this hotel is yours...
Kenapa kau bilang hotel ini milikmu…
I guess it is.
Kurasa begitu.
Well... I'm leaving.
Baik. Aku pergi.
By any chance,
Kebetulan...
do you happen to know if the actress, Hye-ra,
apa kau tahu aktris Hye-ra
would be here today? She won't be here, right?
di sini hari ini? Dia tak ada di sini, bukan?
Hye-ra? You mean our model?
Hye-ra? Maksudmu model kami?
My gosh, sir.
Astaga.
You know what my gorgeous actress is like.
Kau tahu seperti apa aktris cantikku.
Mura.
Mura.
It's been a long time, Mura.
Lama tak bertemu, Mura.
Hye-ra must be doing a photo shoot right now.
Hye-ra pasti sedang pemotretan sekarang.
What did you just say?
Apa katamu?
What's the matter?
Ada apa?
My gosh!
Astaga.
No!
Tidak.
Let go!
Lepaskan!
Mura! It's me, Habaek.
Mura! Ini aku, Habaek.
Mura! Have I become unrecognizable?
Mura! Apa aku tak bisa dikenali lagi?
I'm in a bind.
Aku dalam kesulitan.
Something went wrong on my way here, and I lost the map.
Perjalananku ke sini bermasalah dan petaku hilang.
That's not the only thing I lost!
Bukan hanya itu yang hilang!
There are so many crazy people.
Ada banyak orang gila.
Isn't he that guy who pestered you
Bukankah dia pengganggu
to give him your autograph on his forehead at your signing last week?
yang minta tanda tanganmu di dahinya saat acara minggu lalu?
How dare you touch me?
Beraninya kau menyentuhku?
No, he's not that guy.
Dia bukan pria itu.
By the way, that man is so handsome.
Omong-omong, pria itu sangat tampan.
Too bad.
Sayang sekali.
I'm really sorry, Hye-ra.
Maafkan aku, Hye-ra.
Those are not the right shoes.
Itu bukan sepatu yang tepat.
Finish it up quickly.
Cepat selesaikan.
You punk!
Berengsek!
Come here.
Kemarilah.
What is going on?
Apa yang terjadi?
Hye-ra, you should get out of here.
Hye-ra, kau harus pergi dari sini.
Do your job properly.
Kerjakan tugasmu.
Okay.
Baiklah.
My goodness!
Astaga.
Gosh, what's he thinking?
Astaga, apa yang dia pikirkan?
Wait! Hold on, please. Just a second, please.
Tunggu! Tunggu sebentar.
Wait. He's a patient of mine.
Tunggu. Dia pasienku.
I'll explain everything. Please let go of him!
Aku jelaskan semuanya. Tolong lepaskan dia!
-I said, let go of him. -Goodness!
- Kubilang lepaskan. - Astaga!
Get away from my servant.
Menjauh dari pelayanku.
-Are you okay? -Stop!
- Kau tak apa-apa? - Hentikan.
We'll take care of it, so...
Akan kami urus, jadi...
Sir.
Pak.
-Call the agency. -Okay.
- Hubungi agensi. - Baiklah.
Hey. What do you think you're doing?
Hai. Apa yang kau lakukan?
You should talk it out.
Kau harus membicarakannya.
Why did you hit him?
Kenapa memukulnya?
Who are you?
Siapa kau?
-I'm his guardian. -His guardian?
- Aku walinya. - Wali?
I hit him because he deserved it.
Itu karena dia pantas mendapatkannya.
He's just getting what he deserves.
Dia pantas mendapatkannya.
No one deserves to be hit.
Tak ada yang pantas dipukul.
He shoved our bodyguards.
Dia mendorong pengawal kami.
Look here. People may say you are a goddess,
Dengar. Orang mungkin bilang kau adalah dewi,
but you're just human.
tapi kau hanya manusia.
Once a flower blooms, it wilts and dies.
Saat bunga mekar, bunga layu dan mati.
You think you'll stay beautiful forever, right?
Apa kau akan cantik selamanya?
No. Don't be shocked when you become a wrinkly old woman,
Tidak. Jangan terkejut saat kau menjadi wanita tua keriput
and take care of your mind.
dan jaga pikiranmu.
Come see me. I'll give you a celebrity discount.
Temui aku. Akan kuberikan diskon selebritas.
Let's go.
Ayo.
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH DOCTOR YUN SO-A
KLINIK JIWA BLESSED DOKTER YUN SO-A
Get in.
Masuk.
Why'd you get involved? She would've stopped.
Kenapa kau terlibat? Dia akan berhenti.
Why, you...
Kenapa kau…
You made a mistake.
Kau membuat kesalahan.
Mura is a true goddess.
Mura adalah dewi sejati.
She is a flower that will not wilt or die.
Dia bunga yang tak akan layu atau mati.
Naturally, she won't grow old.
Tentu dia tak akan menua.
I said I was your guardian.
Aku bilang aku walimu.
For the first time ever, I wanted to remove you
Untuk pertama kalinya, aku ingin mengusirmu dari duniamu.
But you don't seem to want...
Tapi sepertinya kau tak mau...
or have any desire to leave.
atau punya keinginan untuk pergi.
You and I live in different worlds.
Dunia kita berbeda.
Fine. Do you really want to meet a god?
Baik. Kau sungguh ingin bertemu dewa?
I must.
Harus.
Fine.
Baik.
Hey, Yeom-mi.
Hai, Seon-mi.
The patient the doctor brought must be a big fan of Hye-ra's.
Pasien yang dibawa dokter
There was a small incident, but it ended without any problems.
Ada insiden kecil, tapi berakhir tanpa masalah.
The patient Ms. Yun brought?
Pasien yang dibawa Nona Yun?
Yes. But I think that patient
Ya. Tapi kurasa pasien itu adalah
was the man we saw yesterday outside Grand Park Hotel.
pria yang kita lihat kemarin di luar Grand Park Hotel.
Really?
Sungguh?
She must use very unique treatment methods.
Pasti metode pengobatannya sangat unik.
She seems very devoted to her patients.
Dia sangat setia pada pasiennya.
She's just a hater. It's nothing new. Forget it.
Dia hanya pembenci. Bukan hal baru. Lupakan saja.
He assaulted one of our people too,
Dia menyerang salah satu orang kita juga,
so he wouldn't complain, right?
dia tak akan mengeluh, 'kan?
If he does,
Jika mengeluh...
we can complain too.
kita bisa mengeluh juga.
-Mr. Kim. -Yes?
- Pak Kim. - Ya?
Shut up.
Diam.
Rest up. I'll come back when things are ready.
Istirahatlah. Aku kembali saat semua siap.
Let's take a ten-minute break. Take a break.
Istirahat 15 menit. Istirahatlah.
-Where are you? -Shanghai.
- Di mana kau? - Shanghai.
What are you doing there?
Sedang apa di sana?
I want to fly.
Aku mau terbang.
This isn't the time to be flying.
Ini bukan saatnya terbang.
Hearing you say that, I guess it is time to fly.
Mendengar ucapanmu, kurasa ini saatnya terbang.
-He's here. -Who?
- Dia di sini. - Siapa?
-Habaek is here! -What?
- Habaek di sini! - Apa?
I can't believe it.
Aku tak percaya.
He showed up looking like a beggar.
Dia muncul seperti pengemis.
Did the red water finally come to the Land of Water?
Apa air merah akhirnya muncul dia Negeri Air?
-What do we do? -Calm down, miss.
- Apa yang kita lakukan? - Tenang, Nona.
He'll come for me too, then.
Dia akan mencariku juga.
I doubt it.
Aku meragukannya.
That idiot lost the map.
Si bodoh itu kehilangan peta.
-What? -He said that isn't all he lost,
- Apa? - Dia bilang tak hanya itu,
but I don't know what he meant. I kicked him out.
entah apa maksudnya. Aku mengusirnya.
Don't forget.
Jangan lupa.
You and I are accomplices
Kau dan aku bersekongkol
with regard to the sacred stone. Got it?
dalam hal batu suci. Paham?
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH
KLINIK MENTAL BLESSED
How dare you bring a girl with you?
Beraninya kau membawa gadis?
The first thing you did in the human world was seduce a girl?
Tindakan pertamamu di dunia manusia merayu seorang gadis?
Habaek is here.
Habaek ada di sini.
I was getting bored anyway. This should be interesting.
Aku mulai bosan. Ini pasti menarik.
Shall we switch over to a mystery, thriller, and suspense movie?
Haruskah kita beralih ke film misteri, thriller, dan ketegangan?
Okay.
Baiklah.
Is a woman who knows a god really in here?
Apa wanita yang tahu tentang dewa ada di sini?
Yes. I think she meets with a god quite often.
Ya. Kurasa dia sering bertemu dengan dewa.
That can't be possible.
Itu tak mungkin.
It wouldn't be surprising for Lord Biryeom.
Kemungkinan besar Tuan Biryeom.
He was like that when he was in the Land of the Sky too.
Dia juga seperti itu saat di Negeri Langit.
Plus, she's a woman.
Ditambah, dia wanita.
Lord Biryeom likes women more than anything.
Tuan Biryeom suka wanita.
-You wait here. -Yes, My Lord.
- Kau tunggu di sini. - Ya, Tuan.
I'll think about why Lady Mura is snubbing you.
Aku akan pikirkan kenapa Nona Mura menghinamu.
-What? Snubbing? -Let's go.
- Apa? Menghina? - Ayo pergi.
Why is it so empty?
Kenapa kosong?
The units haven't been sold yet.
Unitnya belum terjual.
It's been a year, but it's still in this state.
Sudah setahun, tapi masih begini.
Like someone who can read into other people's futures,
Seperti bisa membaca masa depan orang lain,
but have no clue about their own.
tapi tak tahu masa depan sendiri.
-What does that mean? -We're here.
- Apa artinya? - Kita sampai.
Here.
Di sini.
Her name is Jo Yeom-mi. She's my friend.
Namanya Jo Yeom-mi. Dia temanku.
He's Guy B, whom you told me about,
Dia Pria B, yang kau ceritakan kepadaku,
and you're Girl A, the one struggling with her conscience?
dan kau Gadis A, berjuang dengan nuraninya?
You're the one who heard voices about a curse.
Kaulah yang mendengar suara tentang kutukan.
Guy B says he's a god.
Pria B bilang dia dewa.
Let him talk to you.
Biarkan dia bicara denganmu.
He insists he must meet a god.
Dia bersikeras harus bertemu dewa.
You are the closest thing I know to a god.
Hanya kau yang kukenal dekat dengan dewa.
I know. But he refuses medical help, which we studied.
Aku tahu. Tapi dia menolak bantuan medis yang kita pelajari.
So give him a consultation
Jadi, beri dia konsultasi
and figure out what kind of a world he lives in.
dan cari tahu dunia tempat tinggalnya.
I think he's for real.
Kurasa dia sungguhan.
He should be a host to a god.
Dia pasti medium dewa.
What?
Apa?
You look a lot like him.
Kau mirip dengannya.
-I heard from So-a. -Where's Biryeom?
- Kudengar dari So-a. - Di mana Biryeom?
Bring him right now.
Panggil dia.
-I don't know who that is. -You don't?
- Aku tak tahu siapa itu. - Tidak?
Then is Joodong the one you met?
Apa Joodong yang kau temui?
Now, who's Joodong?
Siapa Joodong?
I came because she said you meet with a god.
Aku datang karena dia bilang kau bertemu dewa.
I do, but the god that I serve is neither Biryeom nor Joodong.
Ya, tapi dewa yang kulayani bukanlah Biryeom atau Joodong.
No? Then whom?
Tidak? Lalu siapa?
Do you meet with one of the useless minor deities that fell here?
Apa kau bertemu salah satu dewa kecil tak berguna yang jatuh kemari?
Not a minor deity, either.
Bukan dewa kecil juga.
My god's name...
Nama dewaku...
is Sigmund Freud.
adalah Sigmund Freud.
Okay. Why don't you talk first?
Baiklah. Kenapa tidak kau yang mulai?
You said you heard already.
Katamu kau sudah dengar.
That servant never does anything right.
Pelayan itu tak pernah melakukan sesuatu dengan benar.
Listen, lowly human.
Dengar, manusia rendahan.
I'm the next emperor of deities,
Aku adalah kaisar dewa berikutnya,
the next king of the Land of Water, and the god of water.
raja Negeri Air berikutnya, dan dewa air.
I am Habaek.
Aku Habaek.
Mr. Park Sang-cheol called, saying it'll be the last time for real.
Pak Park Sang-cheol menelepon, katanya itu yang terakhir kalinya.
He sounded resolute.
Dia terdengar tegas.
What does he want?
Apa yang dia inginkan?
Call him and schedule a meeting for tomorrow.
Telepon dia dan jadwalkan pertemuan untuk besok.
I think he's for real.
Kurasa dia sungguhan.
He should be a host to a god.
Dia pasti medium dewa.
You and I live in different worlds.
Dunia kita berbeda.
Whether it's this side or that side,
Entah di sisi ini atau di sisi itu...
he lives in a different world.
dia tinggal di dunia yang berbeda.
It ends here.
Cukup sampai di sini.
You don't have to care anymore.
Kau tak perlu peduli lagi.
You have Vanuatu.
Kau punya Vanuatu.
What the...
Apa...
QUACK
KWEK
-How did it go? -I'll text you Professor Hwang's number.
- Bagaimana hasilnya? - Akan kukirimkan kontak Profesor Hwang.
He's the director of a psychiatric hospital in Gangwon Province now.
Kini dia direktur rumah sakit jiwa di Provinsi Gangwon.
He clearly falls within Professor Hwang's expertise.
Dia spesialisasi Profesor Hwang.
He was the one person who understood me.
Dia orang yang memahamiku.
I see why you struggled so much.
Aku paham kenapa kau kesulitan.
He's beyond what you can treat.
Dia melampaui kemampuanmu.
-Send him there. -Hey, Yeom-mi.
- Kirim dia ke sana. - Yeom-mi.
I signed up for a cooking class. It starts today.
Aku ikut kelas memasak mulai hari ini.
I'm late, so I'm out. Bye.
Aku terlambat. Dah.
Hey!
Hai!
Shoot.
Sial.
Excuse me.
Permisi.
Were you toying with me?
Kau mempermainkanku?
No, that's not it.
Tidak, bukan itu.
You foolish human.
Dasar manusia bodoh.
Don't you believe me?
Kau tak percaya padaku?
-No, that's not it. -You may go.
- Bukan itu. - Kau boleh pergi.
I'll really let you go this time.
Kubiarkan kau kali ini.
It's just that I didn't believe things that are unbelievable.
Aku tak percaya hal-hal yang mustahil.
This was the best I could do for you.
Ini usahaku yang terbaik.
How do you differentiate...
Bagaimana kau membedakan...
what is true from what is not?
yang benar dan tidak?
To you, truth is believing what you want to believe.
Bagimu, kebenaran adalah memercayai yang ingin kau percayai.
Because that is easier. It is less difficult.
Karena itu lebih mudah. Tidak lebih sulit.
That's how you close your eyes to certain truths.
Begitulah kau menutup mata terhadap kebenaran tertentu.
Your dad abandoned us.
Ayahmu menelantarkan kita.
That's what you should assume.
Seharusnya itu yang benar.
You don't know anything.
Kau tak tahu apa-apa.
To you, truth is believing what you want to believe.
Bagimu, kebenaran adalah memercayai yang ingin kau percayai.
Because that is easier. It is less difficult.
Karena itu lebih mudah. Tidak lebih sulit.
That's how you close your eyes to certain truths.
Begitulah kau menutup mata terhadap kebenaran tertentu.
Your dad abandoned us.
Ayahmu menelantarkan kita.
That's what you should assume.
Seharusnya itu yang benar.
Why is the truth...
Kenapa kebenaran...
so important?
begitu penting?
Lord Habaek was right.
Tuan Habaek benar.
This really does make time fly.
Ini memang menghabiskan waktu.
I wonder how it's going.
Aku penasaran.
Should I text?
Haruskah mengirim pesan?
That's right. He can't read.
Benar. Dia tak bisa membaca.
What is that?
Apa itu?
NAMSURI
NAMSURI
-What is it? -Why is Ms. Descendant doing that?
- Apa? - Kenapa Nona Keturunan melakukan itu?
-What? -Why is Ms. Descendant
- Kenapa Nona Keturunan
fighting some man on the roof?
melawan orang di atap?
What are you talking about?
Apa maksudmu?
Oh, no.
Tidak.
She's...
Dia…
Why, that jerk...
Bedebah itu…
Let go.
Lepaskan.
What are you saying, you idiot?
Apa maksudmu, Bodoh?
Oh, no. He keeps pushing her.
Tidak. Dia terus mendesaknya.
He's pushing her!
Dia mendorongnya!
She's falling!
Dia jatuh!
It must be fate.
Ini pasti takdir.
The person who saves her life...
Orang yang menyelamatkan hidupnya...
What are you?
Apakah dirimu?
I told you.
Sudah kubilang.
I'm a god.
Aku dewa.
It must be fate.
Itu pasti takdir
-Your power... -No way.
- Kekuatanmu... - Tak mungkin.
-Long time no see, So-a. -No way!
- Lama tak bertemu, So-a. - Tak mungkin!
Don't fall for me.
Jangan jatuh cinta padaku.
Who are you, really?
Siapa kau sebenarnya?
There's no way out if you fall for me.
Tak ada jalan keluar jika kau suka padaku.
I want to kill him.
Aku ingin membunuhnya.
I met a real god today.
Aku bertemu dewa sejati hari ini.
I am the real god.
Aku dewa sejati.
Why does he keep leeching off of me?
Kenapa dia terus memanfaatkanku?
-I'm sorry. -Want to know a secret?
- Maaf. - Mau tahu rahasia?
I did nothing wrong.
Aku tak bersalah.
I'm the victim.
Aku korbannya.
-Who was he? -How did he...
- Siapa dia? - Bagaimana dia...
Tell me!
Katakan!